May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records
May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records
1830-1988
1839-1952
May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society
6 linear ft.
Records of May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society in Syracuse, NY. Collection includes letters, photographs, newsletters, printed matter, audiotapes, brochures, Order of Worship handouts, etc.
2484317
Biographical History
May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society began in 1838 in Syracuse, New York. Its founders had left the Congregational Church of New England in Boston, preferring to study the gospels for themselves and worship according to individual conscience. The church was originally named "Church of the Messiah." Members of the congregation were active in the community; their second minister, Samuel Joseph May, was a well-known abolitionist and reformer best remembered in Syracuse for his part in the escape of Jerry, a runaway slave, memorialized in the "Jerry Rescue" sculpture in downtown Syracuse's Clinton Square. In 1885 the church moved to James Street and named their new stone building "May Memorial Church" in his honor; some time later the group voted to change their name to May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society Records, comprising the papers and records of seven ministers beginning with Samuel Joseph May, covers over 100 years. Folder titles given in the inventory below are for the most part the original ones, exactly as received; in the few cases where a folder title was supplied by staff, it is given in square brackets [ ].The collection is only roughly organized, divided according to the tenure of each minister:
John Storer, Minister 1839-1844
Samuel Joseph May, Minister 1845-1868
Samuel R. Calthrop, Minister 1868-1911
John H. Applebee, Minister 1911-1929
Waldemar W. Argow, Minister 1930-1941
Robert E. Romig, Minister 1941-1946
Glenn O. Canfield, Minister 1946-1952
John Fuller, Minister, 1961-1973
Nick Cardell, Minister, 1973-1995
Scott Taylor, Minister, 1997-
Contents include letters, photographs, deeds, wills, pew rental contracts, legal papers, marriage records, clippings, articles, books, Orders of Service, Sunday School reports, and many other items.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Applebee, John H.; Argow, Waldemar W.; Calthrop, Samuel R.; Canfield, Glenn O.; Fuller, John C., Rev.; May, Samuel J. (Samuel Joseph), 1797-1871.; Romig, Robert E.; Storer, John, Rev.; May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society.; Unitarian churches -- History.; Unitarian churches -- New York (State); Syracuse (N.Y.) -- Social life and customs.; Correspondence.; Legal files.; Programs (documents); Sermons.; Photographs.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of May Memorial Unitarian Universalist Society, various dates.
Inventory
- John Storer, Minister, 1839-1844
  - Two copies of letter from church members, 1844 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Portrait of John Storer, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Text of memorial plaque, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Xerox copies of archival material gathered by J. Hoefer and I. Baros-Johnson at On. Hist. Soc., UUA and Harvard libraries (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Typed Statements: Origin of the church, Covenant of the Unitarian Congregational Church of Syracuse, Onondaga County Record of meeting to start Unitarian Congregational Society in Syracuse
    Longhand: Signers of Covenant, 5-page history of Society through SJ May ministry. Copy of invitation to Trenton (NY) Church and delegates to installation of John Storer, 1839. (Note from 1866 on funeral of Deacon Peter Vanderkamp.)
  - Diagram of Pews, Church of Messiah 1843 and record of pew sale, Nov. 24, 1843, 12 "deeds." (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letter and request to John Townsend for lot to erect a church, 1840 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Legal papers, 1843; 1844; re building Church of the Messiah (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Consecration of the Church of the Messiah -- Program, copy typed from Christian Register: "Account of Dedication of the Church of the Messiah", Dec. 9, 1843 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Postcard from Margaret T. Smith, re death and burial of John Storer (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Portrait Amelia Bradbury, typed quote from Chase history about her and her school. Four-page historical essay about Syracuse, 1830s and 1840s (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - House of worship subscribers. Mr. Storer's salary subscribers. Sums obtained by Mr. Storer., 1839-1845 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper New York Christian Messenger, 1841-1843; 3 copies (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Samuel Joseph May, Minister, 1845-1868
  - Book of Church Records, May 1, 1870; presented by JPB Storer, leather bound inscribed Alfred Wilkinson, begun by JPBS and continued by SJM. Contains 1838 covenant, membership and marriage records. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Bound book, contains Incorporation of Unitarian Congregational Society in Syracuse, October 4, 1838, recorded by County Clerk Jan. 2, 1839; records of trustee meetings; list of members (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Bound book, inscribed Alfred Wilkinson, May 1, 1870 inside front cover (detached). Record of organizing meeting and covenant; list of names with dates through 1844. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs of SJM, 1944; undated; 1) Original 8 1/2 x 11 1/2. 2) 2 copies 8 x 10 by Charles White of large picture in roller. 3) Copy 5 x 7 SJM and George Emerson. 4) 3 copies: SJM and bridal couple, Post Standard Feb. 13, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - SJM correspondence, 1844-1868; 17 letters to and from SJM dated over years from 1844 when called to Syracuse up to 1868. Terms of employment, loans. Some originals, some copies. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [misc], 1854; 1857,; 1863; 2 Photocopies SJM letters, Nov. 14, 1857 and undated. 2 Typed copies SJM to trustees 1863. 2 typed copies SJM to Friends, 1856. written memo re number of hours, minutes, L.T. May 1854. List of books, George E. May. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Written draft statement SJM mission, 1852 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 4 miscellaneous clippings (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bound book, Recollections of the Antislavery Conflict by SJM. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Xerox copies OHA clippings, 1850-1865 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - [misc], 1846; 10-page typed copy Syracuse Daily Journal, First annual meeting of Syracuse Orphan Asylum. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Articles and correspondence, re busts of SJM at Onondaga Historical Assoc. (OHA) and MMUUS. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Leather notebook listing subscriptions for annuity for SJM. Copies of letters re SJM annuity and hiring S R Calthrop, Oct. 11, 1867 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Text of marble plaque installed in wall of James St. church; cemetery map (1990) site of SJM grave. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 100th anniversary of SJM birthday, undated; programme, description of program, copy of prayer (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Two copies biography of SJM by Joseph May. From "Heralds of a Liberal Faith Vol III, AUA, 1915; mimeographed pamphlet, Xerox copy (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Heretic in Syracuse: Samuel Joseph by Catherine Covert Stepanek, May 1845 - 1873; PhD thesis, 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Notes, talks and sermons, re SJM, typed copies (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Written notes, (John C. Fuller handwriting?) for 111th Jerry Rescue celebration? (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Cornell Library Journal article about SJM by Pease and Pease, "Samuel May: Civil Libertarian.", 1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 5 sermons by Joseph May, 2 Xerox copies of one of them. Xerox copy of title page "Discourse to Cambridge Theological School Graduating Class" SJM, 1847; undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Syracuse Village and City by Carroll E. Smith and Margaret Tredwell Smith. OHA, 1897 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Life of Samuel J. May by George Emerson, Samuel May and Thomas J. Mumford, 2 bound books; SJM letter to Harriet Martineau, 1853 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - In Memoriam. Samuel Joseph May, 2 paperbound copies. Samuel Joseph May: a Memorial Study by Joseph May, 2 paperbound copies., 1871; 1898 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - The Tailor Boy no author, inscribed SJM.Rocks and Shoals: Lectures to Young Men by George E Hopkins, inscribed SJM., 1865; 1870 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Letter remembrance of SJM by AF Pease to E. Lewis, 1928; Xerox copy and typed copy of same (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Photo Rev. Luther Lee. List 4 sources SJM history (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - List of Church members, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - [pew rent], Church of Messiah pew diagrams, 1853; before 1867. Lists of pew holders, 1850-1863, some undated. Pew contracts 1849 ++; receipts 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Original incorporation certificate and 2 typed copies., Mar 12, 1845 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Order of Service, Dedication of Church of Messiah, 1853; 2 copies (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Lists of pledges for debt, building, salary (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - [misc], Accounts, receipts, pledges, 1848-1849. Notice of congregational meeting to hire SJM 1845. Notice of conveyance of land 1848. Quit claim signed by members 1868. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Letters, Letter 1844, Ellsworth Phelps, new organ. Letter 1852, Holbrook, receipt for use of bell. Two letters 1852, B.D. Simmons, new organ proposed and and ordered. 2 letters 1853, from John May re Simmons, progress on organ. Letter 1853, C.D. Kellog Cobb, organ for sale. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Committee report: Plan for "General Committee" of Church of the Messiah., List of 21 men, untitled, undated. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Letter, 1852; Trustees to JG Northrup to repair and pay for damages to house and property (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - [misc], Pew releases and subscriptions to finance rebuilding, 1852 Mar 12, 1845. Reorganization of U. Cong. Society. Registration recorded in village records. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Boston Investigator, Wed. Sept 19, 1855; 4-page weekly newspaper for free thinkers (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Note on supply minister Rev. Joseph Angier, 1859 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - "What Do Unitarians Believe?" Samuel J. May. American Unitarian Association, Boston, MA, undated (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Samuel R. Calthrop, Minister, 1868-1911
  - Five photographs of Calthrop home Primrose Hill (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Seven photographs, Annie Agan (later Mrs. Franklin Chase), Mrs. R. G. Stone, Bronson Alcott, Mary E. Bagg (Mrs. James L. Bagg), W. B. Cogswell, Mary Gormer White, Frederick Rowland Hazard and Mrs. Dora Gannett Sedgwick Hazard (1880). (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Twenty-six photographs, 14 SRC; SRC with two women; John Calthrop brother of SRC; 4 prints together: MMU church, Mrs. Elizabeth Primrose Calthrop, SRC reading, Primrose Hill with SRC on porch; Richard G. Calthrop (son SRC); Large print Mrs. EPC; Elizabeth Calthrop daughter SRC; Henry Cooper reading; Cooper family picnic 1904; MMU church Sunday School, 1897. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photocopies of portraits, 1 of SJM and 2 of SRC (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cassette tape, Mary Cooper remembers SRC. Transcript of interview, William McLennan., 7/23/1983; 7/27/1983 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - [misc], 1870; 1872,; undated; SRC letter April (no year) accept call to Syracuse. Typed copy of report on SRC installation. Typed copy of "Liberal Christian" - SRC asked to stay in Syracuse 2/24/1872. Typed copy of "Syracuse Journal" Aug 8, 1870. Typed copy "The First Grapes" - Amos Padgham (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Letters, 1872; 1875,; 1896,; 1899,; 1906-1907,; 1915; Letter 2/8/72 to call SRC to Detroit. 6/4/75 Roxbury, MA offers presidency of Antioch College. 3/16/96 from Richard S. (Webster?) nephew re "Venezuelan Blue Book" and British Case. 10/7/1899-GB Spaulding invites SRC to 75th Anniversary of first Presbyterian church. 2/5/1906, 11/14/06, 2/12/07 Letters from Andrew D. White of Cornell to SRC. 11/7/1915 letter from JA Brashear, Ed. Fund Commission re "The Supreme Reality," SRC book with letter from Rabbi Levy enclosed Nov. 19, 1915 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Thirty-fifth anniversary of SRC installation, 1903; 3 programs, 2 soft-cover booklets and one hardcover book of speeches at installation service. 3 Benediction Cards. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Two paperbound books, Notes on the Families of Calthorpe and Calthrop, includes slip with author's name; copy of Heirs of John H. Calthrop: Part III: The Lincolnshire Calthrops. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - [articles], Photocopy of a page of The Weekly Recorder Nov 22, 188?. The Craftsman magazine 10/1905 contains SRC article. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Messenger Boy's Christmas Greeting card with verse by SRC from former boys club member. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - [misc], Diagram of streamlined train from Patent #49227. Article by Edith Calthrop Bump, "The Life of Samuel Robert Calthrop" with rejection slip from Reader's Digest 1947. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Handwritten articles by Helen Collins Megrew: "Dr. Samuel Calthrop, Onondaga Creek, Earlier Syracuse.", undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - [misc], Slide photo SRC bust. Card from Mrs. Tracy re SRC bust. Page from D. Ashley re SRC bust. Page from Helen Hiscock Eager re chimes and renovations, James St. church. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Three reprints of "Recollections of the Old Master," Harvard Graduates Magazine, 3, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Poems paperbound by Edith Calthrop Bump and "To My Father" by same (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - [misc], Typescript and 2 carbons resolution of MMUS trustees re death of SRC. Envelope for George N. Cheney. Two typed statements 1/9/1899 from church members with historical information. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - [misc], Clip from MMUS newsletter "Our Wider Ministry" Space-time saying SRC wrote on cardboard. 3 copies. SRC essay "A Day's Life" mounted on cardboard; Two sayings lettered on cardboard; Cardboard and ribbon-bound poetry by SRC, portrait on front cover, photo Primrose Hill on back. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - [writings], The Heaven of the Moon, 2 hardbound copies. Printed folder "Birthday Tribute to Ernst Held..." 6/28/1900. Cardboard and ribbon bound typed The Heaven of the Moon. 3 printed copies "Summer Evening and Night on the Lake" and a 4th copy mounted on cardboard with SRC portrait. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - [writings], Four-page essay by SRC "Sunspots and Weather", typed. Ms. "The Doleful Story of the Cats and the Clover." Notes of SRC sermon "Let Be Light and Light Was." Ms. and typed copy "The Three Hundred and Sixty-Five Sages: a Tale of Hindustan" by SRC. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Patent # 49227 by SRC of Roxbury MA; note about friends whose sons attended SRC's school., 8/8/1865; undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Fifteen-page lecture by SRC "The Transvaal, Armenia, and Venezuela", undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Twenty-two Bible lessons by SRC, 1890-1892 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Sermons, Ring-attached printed sermons and addresses by SRC: 14 delivered at MMU church 1895-1902. 14 delivered elsewhere 1858-1895. Paper-bound copy of sermon "One Lord and His Name One" expanded from original sermon, undated. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Printed booklet "The Primitive Gospel" by SRC. 13 printed sermons in ring binder., 1892; 1903-1913 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Hardcover book The Liberal Club, Buffalo, 1891-1892; includes SRC lecture "The Debt which Religion Owes to Science" (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Book by SRC God and His World, Boston, GH Ellis Co, 1905 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Book by SRC The Supreme Reality, Boston AUA, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Letter from CG Girelius to EC Bump, May 14, 1945; re "The Supreme Reality." (Box 2, Folder 28A)
  - Silver dollar and list of other articles in corner stone MMU church laid, opened in new building East Genesee St., 10/10/1965; 8/11/1884 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Dedication of MMU church: Order of Exercises, 10/20/1885; 1-3/4 copies in very poor condition (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Photographs of James St. Church on cardboard and of SRC, both undated (Box 2, Folder 30a)
  - Bound record of above dedication (one in poor condition) with historical essay and photographs. Sermon by Joseph May, two copies. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - [misc], Typed copy "Notes from Secretary's pre 1885 records," (typed in 1960s.) Clipping from Syracuse Herald J. Jan 14, 1946 re church corner Burnet & State Sts. (originally Church of the Messiah) bought from German Lutheran congregation by Italian Catholic congregation. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Loan application. Mortgage. Bond. Satisfaction of mortgage. Loan application. Envelope Whitman and Barnes mfg. Co., 1871-1872; 1878 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - List of unpaid subscriptions, 1881 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - [misc], 1882; Notice of filing of proposed route of NY, W Shore & Buffalo Railway Co, 2 copies. Copy of agreement to sell church property to NYWS&B 1882. Letter from above RR asking to purchase all or part of U Church property 1882. Letter from U. Soc. Committee to RR requesting proposal for purchase of entire property, original and copy, 1882. Letter from RR "negotiate a price" 1882. Resolved: Committee of MMC empowered to negotiate with RR, undated. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Pencil copy Warranty Deed James St. property. Pencil copy Church title and search etc. Sketch of property., 1884; 1881; undated (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - List, 1884; Church of Messiah trustees, officers, pastor, choir, organist, sexton, building committee, architect (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Four letters and estimate from Butler and Dial re furnaces. Two letters from Alsop Furnace & Stove Co. Two letters from J. F. Pease Furnace Co., 1885-1888 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - [misc], 1872; 1876,; 1904-1905; Form letter to go with subscription card. 1876, subscription policy will continue to replace pew rents. Mailed subscription cards. Treasurer's report May Memorial Sunday school. Special appeal for subscriptions. (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - [Letters], 1906; Letter from J.D. Pennock (Mrs. Pass's father) to report on church ventilation. Letter from Clerk A. Padgham to Salem Hyde re implementing church ventilation by committee on repairs. Letter from James Barnes to Salem Hyde re repairs to the ventilation. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - [Folders 41 and 42 removed, donated to Onondaga Historical Association, March 1997]
  - [misc], 1883; 1888; Undated ? address book: Members of Unitarian Society of Syracuse. 1883 subscription agreement for site and building, list of names and pledges and subscription list for 1888. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - [misc], 1892; 1895,; 1879; 1891 congregation list. 1895 church directory including historical sketch, officers, committees, constitution, Women's Alliance, Boy's Evening Home. 1903 church yearbook, 3 copies. Program and menu from banquet honoring Andrew D. White, 1879. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 2 copies, Text of speeches at SJ May Centennial Celebration; church directory., Oct. 1898; 1907 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - List of subscribers undated. List of members. subscribers, pledges, total income and expenses., 1880-1884 (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - [pew rent], 1897; 1886; Two pew renter consent forms dated 1897, permission to seat others if pew is unoccupied at time of service1884 diagram of pews, annual rent, names of renters. (Recovered from 1884 cornerstone in 1963.) Two copies of 1886 Diagram of pews, annual rent. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - "Miss Ellis' sic Mission" by Mary P. Wells Smith, abridged by Anne E. Howard, Boston, undated; 12-page pamphlet describes Cincinnati woman's outreach via printed word and post office. (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Book given to Church of Messiah by SJM 1868; leather bound record of marriages., 1868-1878 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Record of some marriages by SRC and by WWW Argow. Marriage Record and Certificate., Sept. 1873; 1891-1904,; 1932-1933 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Orders of Service for ordination of Marie H. Jenney, and Albert W. Clark, 1898; 1902 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Order of Ordination Service of Estella Elizabeth Padgham, and her Certificate of membership in Unitarian Ministers Association, undated, 1901 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Old and New, Journal of Des Moines Unitarian Church Anniversary, 1902; mentions E. Padgham and pictures Marie Jenney, minister. (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Order of service, Sunday evening, March 5, 1899; Very poor condition, mounted on cardboard (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Sunday School annual reports, 1902-1903; 1903-04 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - "The Unitarian Calendar" monthly pub. by AUA for MMUS, 1910; 1911; 4 issues (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Preliminary program, National Conference Unitarian and other churches. 20th meeting., 1903; Includes listing of sermon by SRC (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - "Hymn and Tune Book: for the church and the home," Boston, AUA. Theo. L. Poole., 1871 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - "Hymnal: amore Dei," compiled by Mrs. Theodore C. Williams, Boston, George H. Ellis, 1891 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Two stereoscope photos, AW Padgham in England and a residence on South St. Utica, unidentified people. (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Clip from Herald Journal, Report of SRC sermon: "Pure Religion Undefiled.", 11/12/1906 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - May Memorial Church financial statements, Oct. 18, 1909; Sept. 1910 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- John H. Applebee, Minister, 1911-1929
  - Photographs, JHA portrait; JHA in uniform: Mrs. Alice Applebee; JHA 933 Maryland Ave. Syracuse; JHA & AA at home, April, 1914. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Program: Service of Installation JHA, 1911 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - JHA Journal, Jan 1914- Sept 1917 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Five Christmas cards composed by JHA; typed copy of radio talk by JHA., 1934; undated (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - [members in armed services], 1918; Honor Roll: list of church members in armed services. Letter, unsigned from MMUS to editor of the Christian Register. Copy of letter of recommendation for JHA to Red Cross from MMUS Trustees. Application for passport by JHA. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - 4 sermons [by] JHA. "The Wicket Gate" poem by JHA., 1914; undated (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Women's Alliance invitation to dinner in commemoration of birthday of SRC, Monday, Oct. 11, no year given., [1915 or 1926?] (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Two record books of marriages performed by JHA, 1899-1936; 1897-1901 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Shorthand notes by JHA, topic unknown, undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - [resignation], JHA letter of resignation, 1929. Trustees resolution accepting resignation, undated. Proposition to be presented at annual meeting to reconsider JHA resignation. "A Special Fund" for JHA, 3 copies with signed pledges. Copy of letter requesting pledges to Special Fund for JHA. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - [JHA memorial], 1938; Jan. 1938 clippings from Post Standard and Herald Journal on death of JHA. Jan. 1938 JHA memorial service (add date). Remembrance of JHA by Eleanor Rosebrugh (church member) recorded in 1987 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - 30th Annual Meeting of the Unitarian Conference of the Middle States and Canada, at May Memorial Church, Syracuse, Nov. 16, 1914; Order of opening Service and programs for the next two evenings. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Architects blueprints of remodeled front entrance to church building. Typed inventory of property inside building, 6 manuscript pages., Jan. 13, 1916 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Proposed budgets and canvass letters, 1915-1930 (Box 3, Folder 14)